Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Today we're bringing you a lesson about the office, so something related to business,
今天我们带来一节关于办公室的课程，所以跟商务有关，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And in this lesson, we're learning language you can use to tell someone they did a good
在这节课中，我们将学习一些可以用来告诉别人他们做得好的语言，
job.
工作。
Okay, so a job well done.
好的，所以是工作做得好。
You want to praise somebody.
你想表扬某人。
That's right.
没错。
And we're going to listen in as a manager praises his employee on a presentation.
我们将听一段经理表扬员工在演示中的表现。
Okay, so before we listen to the dialogue, let's take a look very quickly at vocabulary
好的，所以在听对话之前，我们先快速看一下词汇，
preview.
预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, we're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue.
嗯，我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
And the first one is a whiz.
第一个是“a whiz”。
Whiz.
“Whiz”。
To be a whiz.
“To be a whiz”。
Okay, so it's an adjective.
好的，所以它是一个形容词。
Somebody is a whiz.
某人是“a whiz”。
That's right.
没错。
And the whiz comes from the word wizard.
“Whiz”这个词来自“wizard”。
Okay, so kind of like a, like a witch, but a guy witch.
好的，有点像女巫，但是男巫。
Yeah, man witch.
是的，男巫。
But so a whiz is someone who is really good at something.
但是“a whiz”是指某人在某方面非常擅长。
Okay, so I can say David is a computer whiz.
好的，所以我可以这样说：David是个电脑高手。
Or Anthony is a math whiz.
或者Anthony是个数学天才。
Okay, so he's really good at computers or he's really good at math or he knows a lot
好的，所以他在电脑方面很擅长，或者他在数学方面很擅长，或者他对数学了解很多，
about math.
数学。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And our second word.
我们的第二个词。
Well, we're going to hear about slides.
嗯，我们会听到关于“slides”。
Slides.
“Slides”。
PowerPoint slides.
“PowerPoint slides”。
Okay, so everyone knows PowerPoint, right?
好的，大家都知道PowerPoint，对吧？
A computer program.
一个电脑程序。
A computer program that you use to make presentations.
一个用来做演示的电脑程序。
And a slide is one page in that presentation.
而“slide”是那个演示中的一页。
Okay, so if you have 10 pages in your PowerPoint presentation, you basically have 10 slides.
好的，所以如果你的PowerPoint演示有10页，你基本上就有10张幻灯片。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So now let's listen to the dialogue for the first time and we're going to see what's happening
所以现在让我们第一次听对话，看看这次商务会议上发生了什么，
in this business meeting.
会议。
And so that concludes my outline for our marketing strategy next year.
那么，这就是我对明年营销策略的概述。
Thank you very much for your time.
非常感谢你们的时间。
Hey, that was quite the presentation.
嘿，这真是一场精彩的演示。
Honestly, I was completely blown away by your strategy outline.
老实说，你的策略概述让我完全震撼了。
I've got to say, Alex, you really wowed me today.
我得说，Alex，你今天真的让我惊叹。
Come on, it was nothing.
别这么说，这没什么。
I'm just doing my job.
我只是在做我的工作。
No, I think you deserve some recognition here.
不，我认为你在这里值得一些认可。
I mean, if I look back on your previous presentations, this is a huge improvement.
我的意思是，如果回顾你之前的演示，这次进步巨大。
Well, Christian did give me a hand with the slides.
嗯，Kirsten确实帮了我一把，处理幻灯片。
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
她在PowerPoint上真是个高手。
And I saw that you took on board my feedback about pricing strategies.
我看到你采纳了我关于定价策略的反馈。
I really appreciate you taking the time to think through my suggestions.
我真的很感激你花时间思考我的建议。
Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
是啊，那是一些好建议。
You made some really good points.
你提出了一些很好的观点。
Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
嗯，我只想说，干得好。
Really, you did a great job.
真的，你做得很好。
All right, well, it sounds like the employee is a little bit shy or embarrassed by receiving
好的，听起来这个员工有点害羞，或者因为收到这么多赞美而感到尴尬，
all of these compliments.
赞美。
Yeah, I guess he's kind of being humble about it.
是的，我想他有点谦虚。
Exactly.
没错。
So why don't we move on to the language now?
那我们为什么不现在进入语言部分呢？
There are so many really useful phrases in this dialogue that I think we're just going
这个对话中有很多非常有用的短语，我想我们今天，
to focus on those today.
就专注于这些。
So let's get started with Fluency Builder.
那么让我们开始流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, so today on Fluency Builder, let's start with our first phrase.
好的，今天在流利度构建中，让我们从第一个短语开始。
The boss was so impressed with the presentation that he said, I was completely blown away.
老板对演示印象非常深刻，他说：“我完全被震撼了。”
To be completely blown away.
“To be completely blown away”。
Okay, so to be completely blown away.
好的，所以是“to be completely blown away”。
Or to be blown away.
或者“to be blown away”。
All right, so what does that mean, to be blown away?
好的，那么“to be blown away”是什么意思？
To be surprised and amazed, but in a very positive way.
感到惊讶和惊叹，但以非常积极的方式。
Okay, so I can say, I'm surprised, I'm amazed, but I'm still not very clear on this.
好的，所以我可以说我感到惊讶、惊叹，但我还是不太清楚。
Why don't we listen to a couple of examples of how we could use this phrase?
我们为什么不听几个例子，看看如何使用这个短语？
Example one.
例子一。
Carl blew me away with his knowledge of political science.
Carl的政治学知识让我惊叹。
Example two.
例子二。
I was blown away when I heard that Jenny and Rick had gotten married.
当我听说Jenny和Rick结婚时，我完全震惊了。
They've known each other for less than a month.
他们认识还不到一个月。
Example three.
例子三。
My parents were blown away when they found out I had a tattoo.
我父母发现我有纹身时，完全震惊了。
Okay, so I think that's a little bit clearer now.
好的，所以我想现在更清楚一点了。
And this is a wonderful way to give your praise to someone when they do something really
这是一个很好的方式，当某人做了非常出色的事情时，给予他们表扬，
amazing.
事情。
Okay, so completely blown away.
好的，所以“completely blown away”。
You blew me away.
“You blew me away”。
That's right.
没错。
Now, what about our second word?
那么我们的第二个词呢？
Well, it's quite similar.
嗯，它很相似。
The boss said that you really wowed me.
老板说：“你确实让我惊叹。”
You wowed me.
“You wowed me”。
To wow someone.
“To wow someone”。
Okay, so it's spelled W-O-W, wow.
好的，它拼写为W-O-W，wow。
So when you wow someone, you make that person go, wow.
所以当你让某人惊叹时，你让那个人发出“哇”的感叹。
Okay, so you impress somebody.
好的，所以你给某人留下深刻印象。
Yep.
是的。
To wow someone.
“To wow someone”。
I can use it as a verb.
我可以把它用作动词。
You wowed me.
“You wowed me”。
I want to wow you.
“I want to wow you”。
Well, I want you to wow me.
嗯，“I want you to wow me”。
Okay, so wow.
好的，所以是“wow”。
Now let's take a look at our third phrase.
现在让我们看看第三个短语。
The guy, he's a little bit shy.
这个人有点害羞。
He's trying to be a little bit humble about, you know, receiving so many compliments.
他试图在收到这么多赞美时表现得谦虚一点，
So he says, oh, it was nothing.
赞美。
It was nothing.
所以他说：“哦，这没什么。”
Really?
“It was nothing”。
It was nothing.
真的吗？
“It was nothing”。
So that's a way of saying it wasn't hard or it's not a big deal.
It's not that important.
所以这是一种说“这并不难”或“没什么大不了的”的方式。
Exactly.
没那么重要。
So if somebody's saying, wow, thank you so much for lending me your car, don't worry
没错。
about it.
所以如果有人对你说：“哇，非常感谢你借给我你的车，别担心。”
It was nothing.
别担心。
“It was nothing”。
All right.
It's a polite way actually to respond to a nice compliment.
好的。
Very good.
实际上，这是一种回应善意赞美的礼貌方式。
So before we move on to our next phrase, let's listen to a couple of examples with it was
非常好。
nothing.
所以在进入下一个短语之前，让我们听几个关于“it was nothing”的例子，
Example one.
例子。
Thanks for lending me your car this week.
例子一。
I really appreciate it.
谢谢你本周借给我你的车。
It's okay, really.
我真的很感激。
It was nothing.
没关系，真的。
Example two.
“It was nothing”。
I can't believe you organized the surprise birthday party.
例子二。
Thank you so much.
我简直不敢相信你组织了惊喜生日派对。
Don't worry about it.
非常感谢你。
It was nothing.
别担心。
Okay.
“It was nothing”。
So I think that's pretty clear.
好的。
Now our final phrase here for fluency builder, the employee said that Kirsten gave him a
所以我想这很清楚。
hand.
现在，流利度构建中的最后一个短语，员工说Kirsten帮了他一把，
Okay.
一把。
So to give someone a hand.
好的。
Give me a hand.
所以是“to give someone a hand”。
“Give me a hand”。
Basically to help someone.
Help me or assist me.
基本上就是帮助某人。
Okay.
帮助我或协助我。
So to help someone, give me a hand or let me give you a hand.
好的。
That's right.
所以是帮助某人，“give me a hand”或“let me give you a hand”。
All right.
没错。
Very good.
好的。
So great phrases in fluency builder today.
非常好。
I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue for the second time.
所以今天流利度构建中有很棒的短语。
We're going to slow it down a little bit so we can catch all these phrases and then we'll
我想是时候第二次听对话了。
come back.
我们会放慢一点速度，这样我们就能抓住所有这些短语，然后我们再回来，
And so that concludes my outline for our marketing strategy for next year.
回来。
Thank you very much for your time.
那么，这就是我对明年营销策略的概述。
Hey, that was quite the presentation.
非常感谢你们的时间。
Honestly, I was completely blown away by your strategy outline.
嘿，这真是一场精彩的演示。
I've got to say, Alex, you really wowed me today.
老实说，你的策略概述让我完全震撼了。
Ah, come on.
我得说，Alex，你今天真的让我惊叹。
It was nothing.
啊，别这么说。
I'm just doing my job.
这没什么。
No, I think you deserve some recognition here.
我只是在做我的工作。
I mean, if I look back on your previous presentations, this is a huge improvement.
不，我认为你在这里值得一些认可。
Well, Kirsten did give me a hand with the slides.
我的意思是，如果回顾你之前的演示，这次进步巨大。
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
嗯，Kirsten确实帮了我一把，处理幻灯片。
And I saw that you took on board my feedback about pricing strategies.
她在PowerPoint上真是个高手。
I really appreciate you taking the time to think through my suggestions.
我看到你采纳了我关于定价策略的反馈。
Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
我真的很感激你花时间思考我的建议。
You made some really good points.
是啊，那是一些好建议。
Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
你提出了一些很好的观点。
Really, you did a great job.
嗯，我只想说，干得好。
Okay, so like we said before, there's a lot of really helpful phrases in here.
真的，你做得很好。
And we're going to look at a few more of these in Putting It Together.
好的，就像我们之前说的，这里有很多非常有用的短语。
Putting It Together.
我们将在“Putting It Together”中再看几个。
Okay, so let's start with the first phrase.
“Putting It Together”。
The boss was quite impressed with him and he said, that was quite the presentation.
好的，让我们从第一个短语开始。
That was quite the presentation.
老板对他印象深刻，他说：“那真是一场精彩的演示。”
All right, quite the presentation.
“That was quite the presentation”。
So this phrase, quite the presentation, it means it was good, right?
好的，“quite the presentation”。
It was special.
所以这个短语“quite the presentation”，意思是它很好，对吧？
It was very good.
它很特别。
Yep, now we can take the noun presentation out and replace it with any other noun.
它非常好。
All right, so I can say, Bob is quite the basketball player.
是的，现在我们可以把名词“presentation”拿出来，用任何其他名词替换。
Why don't we listen now for a few more examples?
好的，所以我可以这样说：Bob是个相当不错的篮球运动员。
Example one.
我们现在为什么不听几个更多的例子？
I heard you are quite the dancer.
例子一。
Can you teach me some moves?
我听说你舞跳得相当好。
Example two.
你能教我一些动作吗？
Carl is quite the ladies' man.
例子二。
He is very good when it comes to talking to girls.
Carl是个相当有女人缘的人。
Example three.
他在和女孩聊天方面很擅长。
Nancy is quite gifted at math.
例子三。
She can solve any math problem you give her.
Nancy在数学方面相当有天赋。
So you're saying in a very good way that something is very good.
她能解决你给她的任何数学问题。
Or special.
所以你是以一种非常好的方式说某件事非常好，或者很特别。
Very special.
非常特别。
All right, so the boss was very impressed with the employee and he said, and I saw that
好的，老板对员工印象深刻，他说，我注意到
you took on board my feedback.
你采纳了我的反馈。
To take on board my feedback.
采纳我的反馈。
Okay, so take on board something.
好的，所以“采纳某物”。
So here, my feedback is my suggestions, right?
这里，我的反馈就是我的建议，对吧？
And when you take on board my feedback, you accept my feedback and you use it.
当你采纳我的反馈时，你接受我的反馈并加以运用。
Okay, so I can say, for example, I want you to take on board my ideas.
好的，所以我可以举例说，我希望你采纳我的想法。
Or Jenny took on board a few of my suggestions.
或者珍妮采纳了我的一些建议。
I was really happy.
我真的很高兴。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So to take on board, to accept and use.
所以“采纳”，就是接受并运用。
All right, so take on board feedback, take on board suggestion, take on board ideas.
好的，所以采纳反馈、采纳建议、采纳想法。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And we have one more phrase, I'm putting it together today.
我们还有一个短语，我今天把它整合起来。
To think something through.
仔细考虑某事。
To think it through.
仔细考虑它。
Okay, so think it through.
好的，所以仔细考虑。
So here, the boss said that he took the time to think through my suggestions.
这里，老板说他花时间仔细考虑了我的建议。
So think through, what does that mean?
所以“仔细考虑”，这是什么意思？
To think carefully about all of the details of something.
仔细考虑某事的全部细节。
Okay, so to take into consideration all the aspects.
好的，就是考虑到所有方面。
Right, so why don't we give an example?
对，那我们为什么不举个例子呢？
If you're thinking through a plan, right?
如果你在仔细考虑一个计划，对吧？
You don't just think about the end, the outcome.
你不只是考虑最终结果。
You want to think about all of the small details, the steps in that plan.
你要考虑所有的小细节，计划中的步骤。
Okay, so maybe I want to buy a new car, but it's a lot of money.
好的，也许我想买一辆新车，但花很多钱。
So I really have to think it through.
所以我真的得仔细考虑。
So you have to think carefully about everything that is involved in buying the new car.
所以你必须仔细考虑买新车涉及的一切。
All the money you're going to have to, you know, not spend on parties.
所有你不得不省下的钱，比如不花在派对上。
Exactly, you have to think it through.
没错，你必须仔细考虑。
You have to analyze it very carefully.
你必须非常仔细地分析。
That's right.
没错。
So let's give a few examples of how we can use this phrase.
那我们举几个例子，看看怎么用这个短语。
Hey, Marco, have you thought through my suggestions?
嘿，马可，你仔细考虑过我的建议了吗？
I can say, you guys are very young.
我可以说，你们还太年轻。
I think you should think it through before you get married.
我觉得你们结婚前应该仔细考虑。
Good advice.
好建议。
Okay, so to think it through.
好的，所以“仔细考虑”。
Okay, so three great phrases and why don't we hear them one more time in our dialogue.
好的，三个很棒的短语，我们为什么不在对话里再听一遍呢？
And so that concludes my outline for our marketing strategy next year.
这就是我明年营销策略的概要。
Thank you very much for your time.
非常感谢您的时间。
Hey, that was quite the presentation.
嘿，那真是个精彩的演示。
Honestly, I was completely blown away by your strategy outline.
说实话，你的策略大纲完全让我惊艳。
I've got to say, Alex, you really wowed me today.
我得说，亚历克斯，你今天真的让我印象深刻。
Come on, it was nothing.
别这么说，没什么。
I'm just doing my job.
我只是做好本职工作。
No, I think you deserve some recognition here.
不，我觉得你值得表扬。
I mean, if I look back on your previous presentations, this is a huge improvement.
我是说，回顾你之前的演示，这次进步巨大。
Well, Christian did give me a hand with the slides.
嗯，克里斯蒂安帮我做了幻灯片。
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
她真是个PPT高手。
And I saw that you took on board my feedback about pricing strategies.
我注意到你采纳了我关于定价策略的反馈。
I really appreciate you taking the time to think through my suggestions.
我真的很感激你花时间仔细考虑我的建议。
Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
是啊，那些建议不错。
You made some really good points.
你提出了一些很好的观点。
Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
嗯，我只想说，干得好。
Really, you did a great job.
真的，你做得很好。
Okay, great dialogue and some interesting phrases for giving praise, right?
好的，很棒的对话，还有一些有趣的表扬短语，对吧？
That's, I think, very important in the workplace.
我觉得这在职场中非常重要。
Yeah, and you know what, I read recently that something like six out of every ten employees
是啊，你知道吗，我最近读到，大约每十个员工中有六个
don't get regular praise from their boss.
得不到老板的定期表扬。
It's very important.
这非常重要。
And in some cultures, well, it's not very common to praise or to give positive feedback
在某些文化中，表扬或给予积极反馈给员工
to their employees.
并不常见。
Yeah, but I think for Western employees, actually, it's really important and it helps them work
是啊，但我认为对西方员工来说，这真的很重要，而且他们听到“干得好”的次数越多，
harder the more times they hear, job well done.
工作就越努力。
Yeah, very good.
是的，非常好。
So now you have the tools that maybe you can use with your employees or...
所以现在你有了工具，也许可以用在你的员工身上，或者...
With your friends.
用在朋友身上。
Yep.
是的。
Okay, so if you have any questions, comments, or doubts, please come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
好的，如果你有任何问题、评论或疑问，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
Yep, Marco and I are always around to help you out.
是的，马可和我随时都在帮你。
So until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye.
那么下次再见，感谢收听，再见。
Bye.
再见。
Happy Marketing University of Florida.
佛罗里达大学营销快乐。